RG 004:031, Cornwall Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Cornwall Probate Court records
1845-2007
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Cornwall District)
10 cubic feet
Record books, 1847-1972; Wills, 1845-2007; Probate files, none.
RG004_031
2011-037 and 2013-012
Historical Note
Cornwall, Litchfield County, Town established in May 1740
The Cornwall Probate District was constituted June 15, 1847, from the Litchfield Probate District. The Cornwall Probate District merged with the Canaan, Norfolk, Salisbury, and Sharon Probate Districts on January 1, 2007 to create the Northwest Corner Probate District. The Northwest Corner Probate District merged with the Harwinton, Litchfield, and Thomaston Probate Districts on January 5, 2011, to create the Litchfield Hills Probate District. The Litchfield Hills Probate District serves the municipalities of Canaan, Cornwall, Harwinton, Kent, Litchfield, Morris, Norfolk, North Canaan, Salisbury, Sharon, Thomaston, and Warren.
Town of Cornwall, Probate District chronology:
May 1740 - October 1742, Hartford District
October 1742 - June 14, 1847, Litchfield District
June 15, 1847 - December 31, 2006, Cornwall District
January 1, 2007 - January 4, 2011, Northwest Corner District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Litchfield Hills District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes, 1-10, 12 and unnumbered volume, 1847-1972. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 12. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Wills, 1845-2007
Probate files, none.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 10. There is an unnumbered volume of bonds and Volume 12 is the second volume of bonds.
Wills in accession 2013-012 are arranged in two alphabetic sequences as received from the probate court.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the wills in accession 2013-012.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Cornwall
Places:
Cornwall (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-037, Record books, 1847-1972, and Accession 2013-012, Wills, 1845-2007, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-10, 1847-1929 were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in accession 2011-037 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on October 28, 2010.
The wills in accession 2013-012 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on September 24, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1847-1972; 6 cubic feet (12 volumes); 2011-037
  - Records, 1847-1860 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1859-1869 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1869-1879 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1879-1886 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1886-1894 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1894-1901 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1901-1908 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1908-1914 (Volume 8)
  - Orders and decrees, 1910-1929 (Volume 9)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1914-1923 (Volume 10)
  - Bonds, 1881-1927 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Bonds, 1928-1972 (Volume 12)
- Wills, 1845-2007; 4 cubic feet; 2013-012
  The dates span for Boxes 1-3 is 1960-2007. The date span for Box 1A is 1845-2007.
  - A - F (Box 1)
  - G - N (Box 2)
  - O - Z (Box 3)
  - A - Y (Box 1A)